Beyond the darkness, lies greatness.
Star Trek Into Darkness is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by J.J. Abrams.
When the crew of the Enterprise is called back home, they find an unstoppable force of terror from within their own
organization has detonated the fleet and everything it stands for, leaving our world in a state of crisis.
With a personal score to settle, Captain Kirk leads a manhunt to a
war-zone world to capture a one man weapon of mass destruction.
As our heroes are propelled into an epic chess game of life and death, love will be challenged, friendships
will be torn apart, and sacrifices must be made for the only family Kirk has left: his crew.
Captain James T. Kirk, played by Chris Pine.
Commander Spock, played by Zachary Quinto.
Lieutenant Nyota Uhura, played by Zoe Saldaña.
John Harrison / Khan, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Dr. Leonard 'Bones' McCoy, played by Karl Urban.
Lieutenant Commander Montgomery 'Scotty' Scott, played by Simon Pegg.
Star Trek Into Darkness is a 2013 American science
fiction action film directed by J.
Abrams, and written by Roberto Orci, Alex Kurtzman, and Damon Lindelof.
It is the 12th installment in the Star Trek franchise and the sequel to the
2009 film Star Trek, as the second in a rebooted film series.
It features Chris Pine reprising his role as Captain James T.
Kirk, with Zachary Quinto, Simon Pegg, Karl Urban, Zoe Saldaña, John Cho, Anton Yelchin,
Bruce Greenwood, and Leonard Nimoy reprising their roles from the previous film.
Benedict Cumberbatch, Alice Eve, and Peter Weller are
also in the film's principal cast.
It was Nimoy's last film appearance before his death in 2015.
Set in the 23rd century, the film follows Kirk and the crew of USS Enterprise as they
are sent to the Klingon homeworld seeking the terrorist John Harrison.
After the release of Star Trek, Abrams, Burk, Lindelof,
Kurtzman, and Orci agreed to produce its sequel.
Filming began in January 2012.
Into Darkness's visual effects were created by
Lucasfilm's Industrial Light & Magic.
The film was converted to 3D during its post-production stage.
It premiered at Event Cinemas in Sydney, Australia, on April 23,
2013, and was released in IMAX theaters in the U.S.
on May 15, 2013, with release in standard-format theaters the next day.
Into Darkness was a financial success and
received positive reviews from critics.
Its gross earnings of over $467 million worldwide have made it the
highest-grossing entry in the Star Trek franchise.
It was nominated for Best Visual Effects at the 86th Academy Awards.
It was followed by Star Trek Beyond in 2016.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, friendship, sequel, alien, futuristic.
The tone is thought_provoking.